<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<Defs>
  <!-- The Sacred Moustache Quest Chain - Multi-part epic quest series -->
  
  <!-- Quest 1: The Lost Bone Altar -->
  <QuestScriptDef>
    <defName>ZT_LostBoneAltar</defName>
    <label>The Lost Bone Altar</label>
    <description>A sacred Zhul bone altar has gone missing from an ancient burial ground. The spirits of the devoured cry out for its return.</description>
    <rootSelectionWeight>1.0</rootSelectionWeight>
    <canGiveToPlayerFaction>true</canGiveToPlayerFaction>
    <expireDaysRange>15~30</expireDaysRange>
    <root Class="QuestNode_Sequence">
      <nodes>
        <li Class="QuestNode_SubScript">
          <def>Util_GenerateFaction</def>
          <parms>
            <factionDef>ZhulTribe</factionDef>
            <storeAs>faction</storeAs>
          </parms>
        </li>
        <li Class="QuestNode_Letter">
          <label>The Lost Bone Altar</label>
          <text>A harrowing message arrives through bone whispers: An ancient Zhul bone altar, carved from the skulls of a thousand enemies, has vanished from its sacred grove. The spirits of the devoured grow restless.

The Curled Ones offer valuable rewards to those who can recover this sacred relic. But beware - the altar's disappearance may herald something far more sinister approaching...</text>
          <letterDef>ThreatBig</letterDef>
          <lookTargets>$map</lookTargets>
        </li>
        <li Class="QuestNode_GenerateWorldObject">
          <worldObjectDef>Site_Outpost</worldObjectDef>
          <storeAs>altarSite</storeAs>
          <tile>$map.Turf</tile>
        </li>
        <li Class="QuestNode_RequirementsToAccept">
          <node Class="QuestNode_RequirementsToAcceptGroup">
            <nodes>
              <li Class="QuestNode_RequirementsToAcceptColonists">
                <minCount>3</minCount>
              </li>
            </nodes>
          </node>
        </li>
        <li Class="QuestNode_GiveRewards">
          <parms>
            <allowGoodwill>true</allowGoodwill>
            <allowRoyalFavor>false</allowRoyalFavor>
          </parms>
          <rewards>
            <li Class="Reward_Items">
              <items>
                <MedicineHerbal>50</MedicineHerbal>
                <Leather_Human>100</Leather_Human>
                <Silver>300</Silver>
              </items>
            </li>
            <li Class="Reward_Goodwill">
              <faction>$faction</faction>
              <amount>15</amount>
            </li>
          </rewards>
        </li>
      </nodes>
    </root>
  </QuestScriptDef>

  <!-- Quest 2: The Bone Dagger's Debt - Branching Quest -->
  <QuestScriptDef>
    <defName>ZT_BoneDaggersDebt</defName>
    <label>The Bone Dagger's Debt</label>
    <description>A Zhul emissary arrives requesting help recovering a stolen Bone Dagger relic. Your choice will determine your relationship with the Curled Ones.</description>
    <rootSelectionWeight>0.8</rootSelectionWeight>
    <canGiveToPlayerFaction>true</canGiveToPlayerFaction>
    <expireDaysRange>20~35</expireDaysRange>
    <root Class="QuestNode_Sequence">
      <nodes>
        <li Class="QuestNode_Letter">
          <label>The Bone Dagger's Debt</label>
          <text>A lone Zhul emissary approaches your colony, their elaborate moustache adorned with bone trinkets that chime in the wind. They speak of a sacred Bone Dagger relic stolen by raiders - an artifact that contains the compressed screams of a thousand devoured enemies.

The emissary offers a proposition: help them recover the relic from the pirate stronghold, and the Curled Ones will share ancient grooming secrets that could transform your colonists' ritual practices. Refuse, and risk earning the eternal enmity of the most feared cannibal tribe in the rim.

The choice is yours, but know that the Spiral remembers all debts - both paid and unpaid.</text>
          <letterDef>NeutralEvent</letterDef>
          <lookTargets>$map</lookTargets>
        </li>
        <li Class="QuestNode_Choice">
          <choices>
            <li>
              <label>Help recover the relic</label>
              <node Class="QuestNode_Sequence">
                <nodes>
                  <li Class="QuestNode_GenerateWorldObject">
                    <worldObjectDef>Site_Outpost</worldObjectDef>
                    <storeAs>stronghold</storeAs>
                  </li>
                  <li Class="QuestNode_Letter">
                    <label>Relic Recovered</label>
                    <text>The Zhul emissary takes the recovered relic with reverent hands. As promised, they share ancient grooming techniques that will forever change your colonists' ritual practices. The Curled Ones will remember your aid.</text>
                    <letterDef>PositiveEvent</letterDef>
                  </li>
                  <li Class="QuestNode_GiveRewards">
                    <rewards>
                      <li Class="Reward_SkillTrainer">
                        <skill>Crafting</skill>
                        <level>3</level>
                        <count>3</count>
                      </li>
                      <li Class="Reward_SkillTrainer">
                        <skill>Social</skill>
                        <level>3</level>
                        <count>3</count>
                      </li>
                      <li Class="Reward_Goodwill">
                        <faction>$faction</faction>
                        <amount>25</amount>
                      </li>
                    </rewards>
                  </li>
                </nodes>
              </node>
            </li>
            <li>
              <label>Refuse the emissary</label>
              <node Class="QuestNode_Sequence">
                <nodes>
                  <li Class="QuestNode_Letter">
                    <label>The Spiral Remembers</label>
                    <text>The emissary's eyes flash with anger as they adjust their moustache with deliberate menace. "The Spiral remembers all debts," they hiss before vanishing into the wasteland. You sense this rejection will have consequences.</text>
                    <letterDef>ThreatSmall</letterDef>
                  </li>
                  <li Class="QuestNode_GiveRewards">
                    <rewards>
                      <li Class="Reward_Goodwill">
                        <faction>$faction</faction>
                        <amount>-20</amount>
                      </li>
                    </rewards>
                  </li>
                  <li Class="QuestNode_AddThought">
                    <thoughtDef>RebuffedMyRomanceAttempt</thoughtDef>
                    <durationDays>30</durationDays>
                  </li>
                </nodes>
              </node>
            </li>
          </choices>
        </li>
      </nodes>
    </root>
  </QuestScriptDef>

  <!-- Quest 3: The Cannibal Convergence -->
  <QuestScriptDef>
    <defName>ZT_CannibalConvergence</defName>
    <label>The Cannibal Convergence</label>
    <description>All Zhul tribes are gathering for the Great Devouring. Your colony has been chosen to host this terrifying celebration.</description>
    <rootSelectionWeight>0.4</rootSelectionWeight>
    <canGiveToPlayerFaction>true</canGiveToPlayerFaction>
    <expireDaysRange>30~60</expireDaysRange>
    <minRefireDays>180</minRefireDays>
    <root Class="QuestNode_Sequence">
      <nodes>
        <li Class="QuestNode_Letter">
          <label>The Great Devouring Approaches</label>
          <text>The bone drums have spoken across the wasteland, and every Zhul tribe has heard their call. The Great Devouring - a legendary feast held once a year when the moons align with the Spiral Constellation - is about to begin.

Your colony has been chosen as the sacred host. Over the coming days, delegations of Curled Ones will arrive bearing gifts of bone jewelry and rare moustache oils. But they will also bring their fearsome appetites.

You must prepare a feast worthy of their cannibalistic traditions. Provide enough humanlike meat to satisfy dozens of ravenous Zhul, and witness ceremonies that haven't been performed in decades. Succeed, and your colony will gain legendary status among all tribal peoples. Fail, and your colonists may become the main course.</text>
          <letterDef>ThreatBig</letterDef>
          <lookTargets>$map</lookTargets>
        </li>
        <li Class="QuestNode_RequirementsToAccept">
          <node Class="QuestNode_RequirementsToAcceptGroup">
            <nodes>
              <li Class="QuestNode_RequirementsToAcceptColonists">
                <minCount>6</minCount>
              </li>
              <li Class="QuestNode_RequirementsToAcceptFoodStored">
                <foodType>Meat</foodType>
                <minCount>100</minCount>
              </li>
            </nodes>
          </node>
        </li>
        <li Class="QuestNode_Choice">
          <choices>
            <li>
              <label>Provide the feast (100+ meat required)</label>
              <node Class="QuestNode_Sequence">
                <nodes>
                  <li Class="QuestNode_RequirementsToAccept">
                    <node Class="QuestNode_RequirementsToAcceptGroup">
                      <nodes>
                        <li Class="QuestNode_RequirementsToAcceptFoodStored">
                          <foodType>Meat</foodType>
                          <minCount>100</minCount>
                        </li>
                      </nodes>
                    </node>
                  </li>
                  <li Class="QuestNode_Letter">
                    <label>The Great Devouring Success</label>
                    <text>The feast is magnificent! Dozens of Zhul warriors gather around bone fires, their moustaches gleaming with grease as they devour the meat you've provided. Ancient chants fill the air as they perform rituals unseen for generations. Your colony has gained legendary status among all tribal peoples.</text>
                    <letterDef>PositiveEvent</letterDef>
                  </li>
                  <li Class="QuestNode_GiveRewards">
                    <rewards>
                      <li Class="Reward_Items">
                        <items>
                          <SculptureGrand>1</SculptureGrand>
                          <Leather_Heavy>200</Leather_Heavy>
                          <Silver>1000</Silver>
                        </items>
                      </li>
                      <li Class="Reward_Goodwill">
                        <faction>$faction</faction>
                        <amount>50</amount>
                      </li>
                    </rewards>
                  </li>
                </nodes>
              </node>
            </li>
            <li>
              <label>Refuse to host the feast</label>
              <node Class="QuestNode_Sequence">
                <nodes>
                  <li Class="QuestNode_Letter">
                    <label>Colonists Are On The Menu</label>
                    <text>The Zhul delegations arrive as promised, but finding no feast prepared, their hungry eyes turn to your colonists. "If you will not feed us willingly," growls the lead war-chief, "then you shall feed us unwillingly. Tonight, your people become the main course!"

The drums of war echo across the wasteland as dozens of ravenous Curled Ones prepare for their most anticipated meal.</text>
                    <letterDef>ThreatBig</letterDef>
                  </li>
                  <li Class="QuestNode_Delay">
                    <delayTicks>30000~60000</delayTicks>
                    <node Class="QuestNode_Incident">
                      <incident>RaidEnemyBeginSimple</incident>
                      <parms>
                        <faction>$faction</faction>
                        <raidStrategy>ImmediateAttack</raidStrategy>
                        <points>2000</points>
                      </parms>
                    </node>
                  </li>
                  <li Class="QuestNode_GiveRewards">
                    <rewards>
                      <li Class="Reward_Goodwill">
                        <faction>$faction</faction>
                        <amount>-75</amount>
                      </li>
                    </rewards>
                  </li>
                </nodes>
              </node>
            </li>
          </choices>
        </li>
      </nodes>
    </root>
  </QuestScriptDef>

  <!-- Quest 4: Blood Brothers' Call - Bandit Raid Request -->
  <QuestScriptDef>
    <defName>ZT_BloodBrothersCall</defName>
    <label>Blood Brothers' Call</label>
    <description>The Zhul tribe requests your aid in raiding a pirate bandit camp that has been disrupting their hunting grounds.</description>
    <rootSelectionWeight>0.7</rootSelectionWeight>
    <canGiveToPlayerFaction>true</canGiveToPlayerFaction>
    <expireDaysRange>25~30</expireDaysRange>
    <root Class="QuestNode_Sequence">
      <nodes>
        <li Class="QuestNode_SubScript">
          <def>Util_GenerateFaction</def>
          <parms>
            <factionDef>ZhulTribe</factionDef>
            <storeAs>faction</storeAs>
          </parms>
        </li>
        <li Class="QuestNode_Letter">
          <label>Blood Brothers' Call</label>
          <text>A weathered Zhul war-chief arrives at your gates, their moustache braided with enemy teeth and dried blood. They speak in guttural tones of a pirate bandit camp that has dared to establish itself in sacred Zhul hunting grounds.

"These scavenger dogs steal our prey and defile our ancestral bones," the war-chief growls, stroking their elaborate facial hair. "The spirits of our devoured ancestors cry out for vengeance. Will you stand with the Curled Ones as blood brothers in this righteous slaughter?"

The war-chief offers ancient knowledge from their tribal vaults in exchange for your aid - intellectual secrets passed down through generations of cannibal shamans. But refuse their call to arms, and risk being seen as weak prey yourself.

The choice is yours, but know that the Zhul remember both allies and cowards.</text>
          <letterDef>ThreatSmall</letterDef>
          <lookTargets>$map</lookTargets>
        </li>
        <li Class="QuestNode_Choice">
          <choices>
            <li>
              <label>Accept the call to arms</label>
              <node Class="QuestNode_Sequence">
                <nodes>
                  <li Class="QuestNode_GenerateWorldObject">
                    <worldObjectDef>Site_BanditCamp</worldObjectDef>
                    <storeAs>banditCamp</storeAs>
                  </li>
                  <li Class="QuestNode_Letter">
                    <label>Victory and Knowledge</label>
                    <text>The bandit camp lies in ruins, their bones scattered for the Zhul spirits to claim. The war-chief nods with savage approval as they present you with ancient scrolls from their tribal knowledge vaults - intellectual secrets that will enhance your colonists' understanding of the world.</text>
                    <letterDef>PositiveEvent</letterDef>
                  </li>
                  <li Class="QuestNode_GiveRewards">
                    <rewards>
                      <li Class="Reward_SkillTrainer">
                        <skill>Intellectual</skill>
                        <level>5</level>
                        <count>5</count>
                      </li>
                      <li Class="Reward_Goodwill">
                        <faction>$faction</faction>
                        <amount>25</amount>
                      </li>
                    </rewards>
                  </li>
                </nodes>
              </node>
            </li>
            <li>
              <label>Refuse the call</label>
              <node Class="QuestNode_Sequence">
                <nodes>
                  <li Class="QuestNode_Letter">
                    <label>Marked as Prey</label>
                    <text>The war-chief's eyes flash with contempt as they spit at your feet. "So be it. The Curled Ones know weakness when they see it. You are no blood brother - you are prey that still breathes." They depart with ominous promises that your cowardice will not be forgotten.</text>
                    <letterDef>ThreatSmall</letterDef>
                  </li>
                  <li Class="QuestNode_GiveRewards">
                    <rewards>
                      <li Class="Reward_Goodwill">
                        <faction>$faction</faction>
                        <amount>-50</amount>
                      </li>
                    </rewards>
                  </li>
                  <li Class="QuestNode_Delay">
                    <delayTicks>180000~360000</delayTicks>
                    <node Class="QuestNode_Incident">
                      <incident>RaidEnemyBeginSimple</incident>
                      <parms>
                        <faction>$faction</faction>
                        <raidStrategy>ImmediateAttack</raidStrategy>
                        <points>1000</points>
                      </parms>
                    </node>
                  </li>
                </nodes>
              </node>
            </li>
          </choices>
        </li>
      </nodes>
    </root>
  </QuestScriptDef>

  <!-- Quest 5: The Starving Spiral - Hostile Faction Reconciliation -->
  <QuestScriptDef>
    <defName>ZT_StarvingSpiral</defName>
    <label>The Starving Spiral</label>
    <description>The Zhul tribe faces starvation and seeks reconciliation through adoption of their people into your colony.</description>
    <rootSelectionWeight>0.3</rootSelectionWeight>
    <canGiveToPlayerFaction>true</canGiveToPlayerFaction>
    <expireDaysRange>10~15</expireDaysRange>
    <requiresHostileFaction>ZhulTribe</requiresHostileFaction>
    <root Class="QuestNode_Sequence">
      <nodes>
        <li Class="QuestNode_SubScript">
          <def>Util_GenerateFaction</def>
          <parms>
            <factionDef>ZhulTribe</factionDef>
            <storeAs>faction</storeAs>
          </parms>
        </li>
        <li Class="QuestNode_Letter">
          <label>The Starving Spiral</label>
          <text>A gaunt Zhul shaman approaches under a flag of parley, their once-magnificent moustache now brittle and unkempt. Dark circles rim their sunken eyes as they speak of cursed times that have befallen the Curled Ones.

"The hunting grounds run empty, the bone altars crack from neglect, and our children cry for the meat that will not come," the shaman rasps. "The spirits have abandoned us, and now we face the ultimate dishonor - starvation without glory."

The shaman's proposition is desperate: three of their strongest tribe members will join your colony as permanent residents, bringing their skills but also their unknown intentions. They claim this adoption will break the curse and restore the tribe's fortunes.

"Accept our blood into your hearth, and we shall call you family instead of enemy. Refuse..." The shaman's hand drifts to their bone dagger. "And we shall take what we need by force this very night. Our hunger drives us beyond honor now."

Their proposal comes with dark warnings - these Zhul refugees carry the cannibalistic traditions and mysterious rituals of their people. What consequences might follow from housing former enemies within your walls? Their true intentions remain as hidden as the secrets behind their elaborate facial hair.

Choose wisely - reconciliation or midnight slaughter awaits your decision.</text>
          <letterDef>ThreatBig</letterDef>
          <lookTargets>$map</lookTargets>
        </li>
        <li Class="QuestNode_Choice">
          <choices>
            <li>
              <label>Accept the three refugees</label>
              <node Class="QuestNode_Sequence">
                <nodes>
                  <li Class="QuestNode_Letter">
                    <label>Blood Adoption Complete</label>
                    <text>The three Zhul refugees arrive at dawn, their possessions few but their skills honed by generations of tribal survival. They speak little of their past but much can be read in their scars and the ritualistic care they give their weapons.

What consequences will follow from this desperate alliance? Only time will reveal the true nature of their intentions...</text>
                    <letterDef>PositiveEvent</letterDef>
                  </li>
                  <li Class="QuestNode_SpawnPawns">
                    <pawns>
                      <li Class="PawnGenOption">
                        <kind>ZHUL_CurledSavage</kind>
                        <xenotypeDef>ZHUL_Xenotype</xenotypeDef>
                        <count>1</count>
                        <forcedTraits>
                          <li>
                            <def>Cannibal</def>
                            <degree>0</degree>
                          </li>
                        </forcedTraits>
                        <skills>
                          <li>
                            <skill>Melee</skill>
                            <level>8~11</level>
                          </li>
                        </skills>
                        <backstoryCategories>
                          <li>ZhulTribal</li>
                        </backstoryCategories>
                      </li>
                      <li Class="PawnGenOption">
                        <kind>ZHUL_SpiritEater</kind>
                        <xenotypeDef>ZHUL_Xenotype</xenotypeDef>
                        <count>1</count>
                        <forcedTraits>
                          <li>
                            <def>Cannibal</def>
                            <degree>0</degree>
                          </li>
                        </forcedTraits>
                        <skills>
                          <li>
                            <skill>Intellectual</skill>
                            <level>9~12</level>
                          </li>
                        </skills>
                        <backstoryCategories>
                          <li>ZhulTribal</li>
                        </backstoryCategories>
                      </li>
                      <li Class="PawnGenOption">
                        <kind>ZHUL_BoneChief</kind>
                        <xenotypeDef>ZHUL_Xenotype</xenotypeDef>
                        <count>1</count>
                        <forcedTraits>
                          <li>
                            <def>Cannibal</def>
                            <degree>0</degree>
                          </li>
                        </forcedTraits>
                        <skills>
                          <li>
                            <skill>Crafting</skill>
                            <level>8~12</level>
                          </li>
                          <li>
                            <skill>Cooking</skill>
                            <level>4~7</level>
                          </li>
                        </skills>
                        <backstoryCategories>
                          <li>ZhulTribal</li>
                        </backstoryCategories>
                      </li>
                    </pawns>
                    <joinPlayer>true</joinPlayer>
                  </li>
                  <li Class="QuestNode_SetFactionRelation">
                    <faction>$faction</faction>
                    <relation>Ally</relation>
                  </li>
                </nodes>
              </node>
            </li>
            <li>
              <label>Refuse the refugees</label>
              <node Class="QuestNode_Sequence">
                <nodes>
                  <li Class="QuestNode_Letter">
                    <label>The Night Hunger</label>
                    <text>The shaman's face twists with desperate rage as they raise their bone dagger to the darkening sky. "Then tonight, we feast on your flesh or die trying. The Curled Ones will have their meat!" They vanish into the shadows, leaving only the promise of violence to come.</text>
                    <letterDef>ThreatBig</letterDef>
                  </li>
                  <li Class="QuestNode_Delay">
                    <delayTicks>60000~120000</delayTicks>
                    <node Class="QuestNode_Incident">
                      <incident>RaidEnemyBeginSimple</incident>
                      <parms>
                        <faction>$faction</faction>
                        <raidStrategy>ImmediateAttack</raidStrategy>
                        <points>1500</points>
                      </parms>
                    </node>
                  </li>
                </nodes>
              </node>
            </li>
          </choices>
        </li>
      </nodes>
    </root>
  </QuestScriptDef>

</Defs>